Nilva, Daniel Photograph Collection 5969 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Daniel Nilva Photograph Collection
1936-1962
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Nilva, Daniel
5969 P
1.25 cubic feet
1.2 linear ft.
Black-and-white negatives.
5743731
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 24, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 10, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Daniel Nilva was born to Russian Jewish immigrant parents, in New York City on March 7, 1914.
Nilva attended Cooper Union in the 1930's, though he never graduated he met some lifelong friends, Bernard Seaman, a labor cartoonist, Morris Stone, later an official with the American Arbitration Association, and Dr. Valentine Gregory Burtan, a heart specialist who had been imprisoned on a conterfeiting charge.
In 1933 he started working as a photographer for the Education Department of Local 22, Dressmakers, of the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. He also was a photographer for the ILGWU newspaper 'Justice'. He did some freelance work for the Bookkeepers Stenographers and Accountants Union's newspaper, 'The Ledger'.
His job with Local 22 only lasted 4 years. By the 1950's, after having trouble finding the right position, he was working as a freelance photographer in New York City, many of his clients were labor unions and progressive organizations.
Nilva's health took a turn in the 1960's when he suffered a heart attack, so he had to cut back on the amount of work he could do.
Daniel Nilva passed away September 15, 1984 as a result of another heart attack.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: Guide to the Daniel Nilva Photographs at the Tamiment Library and Robert F Wagner Labor Archive
Clothing trade; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982; Nilva, Daniel; Zimmerman, Charles S., 1896-1983; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5743731
- D.D. 25th Anniversary (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Garment District Negs. - "With These Hands" [info. From original box]
- Local 142 - Hyde Park -- 8/23/1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Local 34 - Pickets Bellas Hess -- 1/20/1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- TWU - TV-BCAST -- 12/4/1957 -- Ch. 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Boston Barons - M.S.B. Mayan -- 11/1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- RWDSU Strike -- 7/14/1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- A.A.A. Show -- 7/12/1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- ILGWU Pickets - Lane Bryant -- 5/2/1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minimum Wage Demand (Box 1, Folder 9)
- ILGWU Convention (1940) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- ILGWU (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Not labeled (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Unity -- 6/1957 -- Spielman Boy (Box 1, Folder 13)
- AFL-CIO Convention -- 12/5/1955 -- 1st Day (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Jinx Show ILG Art -- 10/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- ILGWU Pickets -- 35th St. -- 4/28/1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- ILG Houses -- 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Local 22 -- Boat ride -- 8/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Jam Session -- 2/8/1958 -- Central Plaza (Box 2, Folder 5)
- D.D. 25th Anniv. - M.S.G. - Unity House (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Dress Strike -- 3/1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Local 155 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Columbia Garment Union -- 3/1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Unity House -- Labor Day -- 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 1940 ILGWU Convention (Box 2, Folder 11)
- TWU American Airlines Picketing -- 4/25/1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- AAA -- 7/11/1957 -- Rehearsal (Box 2, Folder 13)
- ARMO Picketing (Box 2, Folder 14)
- ILGWU - Co-Operative Village - Movie Premier (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Unlabeled (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Movie Premier (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Strike Meeting MSG - ILGWU 1936 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- MSG Dress Strike Meeting -- 3/1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- ILGWU (Box 2, Folder 20)
- ILGWU Parade (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Parade (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Housing Project (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Local 23 -- film strip #1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Local 23 -- film strip #2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Member Meet Man Center -- 6/17/1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- ILGWU - 99 -- 8/27/1959 -- Misc. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- ILGWU - 99 -- 9/3/1959 -- Misc. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- ILGWU - 99 -- 10/7/1959 -- Negotiations at headquarters (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Local 99 -- 1/14/1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- ILGWU - Local 105 -- 6/17/1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- ILGWU - Local 105 -- 7/1/1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- ILGWU - Local 105 -- 9/15/1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- ILGWU Local 105 -- 10/8/1959 -- Marty Cohen at ILGWU Institute (Box 3, Folder 11)
- ILGWU Local 105 -- 11/25/1959 -- Severance Pay (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Local 105 - ILGWU -- 3/3/1960 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Local 10 - Cutters Graduation - 6/28/1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Local 20 - Lus Lunch NCRS - 11/18/1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Local 30 - Ratification Meeting (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Local 22 - Garment Workers Retirement - 8/9/1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Local 22 - Membership Meeting Manhattan Center - 9/28/1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Local 22 - Committee: Puerto Rico - 10/27/1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Local 22 - Puerto Rican trip - 1/11/1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Local 22 - Zimmerman - $5,000 to Paul Jannings - 2/3/1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Local 22 - Petitions on Social Security - 7/5/1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Local 22 - Send-off Party for Zimmerman - Hotel Astor - 7/12/1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Local 22 - CS Zimmerman return from Puerto Rico - 8/16/1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Local 22 - Liberal Party Club Hotel Diplomat - 9/25/1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Local 22 - Opening of Training School - 11/27/1956 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- B. Cl's Clerking Students High School of Fashion - 12/17/1956 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Local 22 Retirement Davidson - Farwell Springer Astor Hotel - 1/4/1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Local 22 - Rent Petitions - 1/30/1957 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Local 22 - Washington Busses - 5/17/1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Local 22 - Member Meeting - 10/23/1957 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Local 22 - Shop Retirees - Rappaports - 10/26/1957 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Local 22 - Member Meeting Manhattan Center - 1/8/1958 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Local 22 - Isidore Balshau - 3/31/1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Local 22 - Kelsen presents clock to Manager Baklaw - 10/6/1958 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Local 22 - Spanish chorus - 3/30/1959 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Local 22 - Union label girls - Jack Lernoesky, Saby -- 3/30/1959 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Local 22 - Retirees - Building 3 Restaurant -- 4/2/1959 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Local 22 - Art Students' Works at Women's International Exposition - 11/8/1959 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Local 22 - by meeting - 2/17/1960 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Local 22 - Workman's Circle - 3/31/1960 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Local 22 - Scholarship Winners - 7/27/1960 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Local 22 - Student - Mina Goldman - 4/29/1961 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Local 22 - Israel Bahlau - 1/23/1962 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Local 22 - C.S. Zimmerman - voting election (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Local 22 - affair (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Local 22 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Local 23 - Heads - B. CEO, Manager & Educational Director - 9/17/1957 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Local 23 - Mural - 8/25/1959 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Local 23 - Vacation Checks, Manhattan Center - 5/26/1960 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Local 23 - Executive Board - 1/15/1962 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Local 23 - Miscellaneous shots (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Local 30 - Designer - 8/6/1956 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Local 32 - Puerto Rican delegation Dinner Cavanaugh's restaurant - 5/21/1956 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Local 32 - Bali Shop meet, 932 Broadway - 3/2/1959 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Local 32 - Misc. Shots - 4/3/1959 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Local 32 - Picket line Poirette Foundation - 10/20/1959 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Local 32 - off to Hyde Park - 6/18/1960 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Local 32 - Member meeting Roosevelt - 1/20/1962 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Local 32 - Misc. Pictures (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Local 32- East Harlem Social Education, Center, Educational Dept., ILGWU Debate (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Local 35 -- 10/11/1957 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Local 35 - 4/21/1959 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Local 35 - 11/4/1959 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Local 35 - 2/12/1960 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Local 35 - 3/17/1960 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Local35 - 10/19/1960 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Local 35 - 2/28/1961 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Local 35 - 11/31/1961 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Local 35 1/18/1962 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Local 40 - 2/21/1956 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Local 40 - Strike meet (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Local 60 - 2/7/1956 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Local 60 - 7/29/1957 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Local 60 - 3/26/1958 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Local 60 - 7/14/1959 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Local 60 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Local 62 - 3/5/1957 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Local 62 - 5/16/1957 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Local 62 - 5/21/1957 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Local 62 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Local 62 - 11/18/1958 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Local 62 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Local 62 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- Local 62 (Box 4, Folder 72)
- Local 62 (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Local 66 - 10/28/1955 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Local 66 - 3/20/1956 (Box 4, Folder 75)
- Local 66 - 4/10/1956 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Local 66 - 6/28/1956 (Box 4, Folder 77)
- Local 66 - 10/8/1956 (Box 4, Folder 78)
- Local 66 - 11/12/1957 (Box 4, Folder 79)
- Local 66 - 1/7/1958 (Box 4, Folder 80)
- Local 66 - 6/29/1961 (Box 4, Folder 81)
- Local 66 - 3/20/1962 (Box 4, Folder 82)
- Local 66 - 4/10/1962 (Box 4, Folder 83)
- Local 66 (Box 4, Folder 84)
- Local 85 - 9/12/1956 (Box 4, Folder 85)
- Local 89 - 3/21/1959 (Box 4, Folder 86)
- Local 89 - 9/27/1961 (Box 4, Folder 87)
- Local 89 - 12/1/1961 (Box 4, Folder 88)
- Local 98 - 6/18/1955 (Box 4, Folder 89)
- Local 98 - 5/17/1957 (Box 4, Folder 90)
- Local 99 - 11/26/1955 (Box 4, Folder 91)
- Local 99 - 7/16/1956 (Box 4, Folder 92)
- Local 99 - 7/17/1956 (Box 4, Folder 93)
- Local 99 - 5/17/1957 (Box 4, Folder 94)
- Local 99 - 10/26/1957 (Box 4, Folder 95)
- Local 99 - 11/26/1957 (Box 4, Folder 96)
- Local 99 - busses to Washington - 10/23/1958 (Box 4, Folder 97)
- Local 99 -- 11/17/1958 (Box 4, Folder 98)
- Local 99 - 12/1/1958 (Box 4, Folder 99)
- Local 99 - 4/13/1959 (Box 4, Folder 100)
- Local 99 - 4/18/1959 (Box 4, Folder 101)
- Local 99 - 12/8/1959 (Box 4, Folder 102)
- Local 99 - 1/18/1960 (Box 4, Folder 103)
- Local 99 - 3/23/1960 (Box 4, Folder 104)
- Local 99 - 4/16/1960 (Box 4, Folder 105)
- Local 99 - 5/11/1960 (Box 4, Folder 106)
- Local 99 - 9/24/1960 (Box 4, Folder 107)
- Local 99 - 10/25/1960 (Box 4, Folder 108)
- Local 99 - 10/27/1960 (Box 4, Folder 109)
- Local 99 - 12/13/1960 (Box 4, Folder 110)
- Local 99 - 2/8/1961 (Box 4, Folder 111)
- Local 99 - 2/20/1961 (Box 4, Folder 112)
- Local 99 - 12/13/1961 (Box 4, Folder 113)
- Local 99 - 2/13/1962 (Box 4, Folder 114)
- Local 99 - 2/19/1962 (Box 4, Folder 115)
- Local 99 (Box 4, Folder 116)
- Local 99 (Box 4, Folder 117)
- Local 105 - 8/23/1955 (Box 4, Folder 118)
- Local 105 - 2/20/1956 (Box 4, Folder 119)
- Local 105 - 3/6/1956 (Box 4, Folder 120)
- Local 105 - 8/3/1956 (Box 4, Folder 121)
- Local 105 - 2/26/1958 (Box 4, Folder 122)
- Local 105 - 11/25/1958 (Box 4, Folder 123)
- Local 105 - 11/29/1958 (Box 4, Folder 124)
- Local 105 - 12/5/1958 (Box 4, Folder 125)
- Local 105 - 4/9/1959 (Box 4, Folder 126)
- Local 105 - 6/5/1959 (Box 4, Folder 127)
- Local 105 - 6/30/1959 (Box 4, Folder 128)
- Local 105 - 7/14/1959 (Box 4, Folder 129)
- Local 105 - 1/16/1960 (Box 4, Folder 130)
- Local 105 - 3/15/1960 (Box 4, Folder 131)
- Local 105 - 3/17/1960 (Box 4, Folder 132)
- Local 105 - 3/21/1960 (Box 4, Folder 133)
- Local 105 - 2/4/1961 - 20th Anniversary Affair (Box 4, Folder 134)
- Local 105 - 11/20/1961 (Box 4, Folder 135)
- Local 105 - 2/6/1962 (Box 4, Folder 136)
- Local 105 - 3/6/1962 (Box 4, Folder 137)
- Local 105 - 21 st. Anniversary Affair (Box 4, Folder 138)
- Local 117 - 3/30/1960 (Box 4, Folder 139)
- Local 132 - 9/18/1956 (Box 4, Folder 140)
- Local 132 - 9/18/1956 (Box 4, Folder 141)
- Local 132 - 5/17/1957 (Box 4, Folder 142)
- Local 142 - 8/23/1958 (Box 4, Folder 143)
- Local 142 - 8/23/1958 (Box 4, Folder 144)
- ILGWU 142 - 6/29/1958 (Box 4, Folder 145)
- Local 155 - 12/9/1955 (Box 4, Folder 146)
- Local 155 - 4/20/1959 (Box 4, Folder 147)
- Local 155 - 12/22/1960 (Box 4, Folder 148)
- Local 169 - 10/21/1958 (Box 4, Folder 149)
- Local 155 - June 27-29, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Massagas Union -- 9/10/1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- UDC - Unity Weekend -- 9/7/1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Unity -- 6/1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- European Trip -- August/September 1951 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Nat'l. Committee for Rural Schools (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Rina Dubinsky Unity House -- 9/13/1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- David Dubinsky playing Gin Rummy 9/1953 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Rina Dubinsky - Birthday Party at 1710 -- 1/23/1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Dress Joint Board - 10,000th Retiree -- 10/23/1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Amal. Clothing Workers -- 3/12/1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- ILGWU - Garment Workers and the Heat -- 8/4/1955 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Amal. Clothing Workers - Union Label Agreement - 9/7/1955 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- ILG Headquarters -- 9/10/1955 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- ILGWU - Dedication -- 10/22/1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Columbia Pictures - Additional Shooting Market Exteriors (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Columbia Pictures - Sculpture & Sketching - Harry Kleiner - 3/1956 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Columbia Pictures - 3/29/1956 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Columbia Pix - Harry Kleiner Shops, etc. -- 3/1956 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Columbia Pictures - Spanish Harlem -- 4/17/1956 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- ILGWU -- Graduation - New Yorker -- 5/23/1956 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- ILGWU -- Training Institute at Hochmann's Office -- 6/21/1956 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- ILGWU - Health Mobile -- 8/3/1956 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Amal. Clothing Workers -- 8/10/1956 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Emanuel Celleir (Congressman) - laundry Workers Joint Board -- 10/4/1956 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- David Dubinsky, 25th Anniversary -- 6/13/1957 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Charles S. Zimmerman - 11/8/1957 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- C.S. Zimmerman -- 11/12/1957 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers -- 6/3/1958 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers - 1/21/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers - Picketing Harry's Men's Shop -- 2/27/1959 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers Joint Board - 3/10/1959 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- ILGWU Convention Badge -- 4/17/1959 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- CS Zimmerman arriving in NY -- Miami Beating -- 5/22/1959 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- ILGWU Press Conference -- C.S. Zimmerman Beating -- 5/24/1959 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers - Shirt Workers Joint Board - Commodore Harry Gelman, Retirement -- 7/2/1959 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Dress Joint Board - Strikers -- 7/22/1959 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Dress Joint council -- 1/11/1961 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Dress Joint council -- 3/30/1961 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers -- 10/19/1961 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- ILG Dress Joint Council - Astor Hotel - 1/17/1962 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Anniversary Convention (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Art Exhibit (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Award (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Basketball (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Ben Shlenger (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Charles S. Zimmerman (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Columbia Pictures (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Convention seating (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Dubinsky - 40th Anniversary (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Dubinsky (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Garment Shop (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Garment Workers (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Gluck & Cohen (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Group Outdoor Photo (Box 5, Folder 55)
- ILGWU - 40th Anniversary Welcome Desserts (Box 5, Folder 56)
- ILG - AFL-CIO Convention (Box 5, Folder 57)
- ILG Anniversary (Box 5, Folder 58)
- ILGWU Speaker (Box 5, Folder 59)
- ILG Union Label (Box 5, Folder 60)
- Labor Sydney Hillman (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Male Garment Worker modifying shirt (Box 5, Folder 62)
- Nelson Convention (Box 5, Folder 63)
- Outdoor Group picture (Box 5, Folder 64)
- Speaker (Box 5, Folder 65)
- Speaker (Box 5, Folder 66)
- UDC - photo (Box 5, Folder 67)
- Unity House (Box 5, Folder 68)
- Unity House (Box 5, Folder 69)
- Unity House (Box 5, Folder 70)
- Unity Office Staff (Box 5, Folder 71)